obsidianportal.com 2013-09-30

# Obsidian Portal - Campaign websites for Dungeons and Dragons and other tabletop RPGs

Obsidian Portal is an interactive content management site for tabletop role-playing games. Rather than trying to automate the playing of the game, Obsidian Portal provides tools to help automate the storytelling. You do not need to be registered to search or view public campaigns, characters, items, and profiles on Obsidian Portal, however you must be a registered member of Obsidian Portal to post. 

## Our Commitment To Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. 

## Information Collection

Obsidian Portal collects personal information in the following ways: 

1\. Account Sign Up 

When a new account is created, we ask the user to supply a username, password, and e-mail address.  The username is chosen by the user and does not constitute sensitive personal information.  It is the primary means of identifying the user throughout the site, including the forums.  The password is considered sensitive personal information and is kept securely and never shared with third parties.  The e-mail address is considered sensitive personal information and is used as detailed below. 

2\. Campaign Creation 

When a new campaign is created, we ask for an approximate physical address for where the game is played.  We encourage using only an approximate address such as the street name or nearby main intersection and strong discourage users from entering their actual address. 

3\. Campaign Invitations>

When a user sends invitations to join a campaign, we ask for the e-mail address of the invitee.  This e-mail address is never shared with third parties. 

4\. Automated Tracking 

Obsidian Portal automatically receives and records certain "traffic data" on our server’s logs from your browser including, but not limited to, your ip address, operating system, Obsidian Portal cookie information, and the page you requested. 

## The Way We Use Information

Obsidian Portal uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in campaigns, game content generation, and the forums.  Obsidian Portal never shares e-mail addresses with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

We use "traffic data" to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users, but we don’t track which terms a particular user enters. 

Obsidian Portal may create aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don’t track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

Advertisements shown to you may be related to textual information, such as metadata and notes, associated with the photo you are seeing, or the search term you entered. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. 

## Cookies

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can’t read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Obsidian Portal uses cookies to provide the "remember me" functionality upon login. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you’ve set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. 

## Our Commitment To Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.  We periodically review our security procedures, and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our users. 

## Our Commitment To Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important.  Consistent with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. 

## Disclosure To Third Parties

In order to provide our users with the best possible experience, Obsidian Portal may partner with third parties to provide services.  An example of this would be to provide player matching services to help existing campaigns fill an opening with a new player. 

To provide such services, Obsidian Portal will, with your consent, provide campaign address information to third parties.  Under no circumstances will your e-mail address be made available. 

In addition, Obsidian Portal may disclose your personal information in order to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

## Opt-out Policy

1\. Obsidian Portal provides the ability to opt-out of e-mail newsletters by updating the user’s profile and choosing not to receive e-mail updates. 

2\. Obsidian Portal provides the ability to opt-out of campaign information sharing to third parties by updating the campaign information and choosing not to publish to third parties. 

3\. You can choose to make your information public for anyone to access, restrict access to a limited number of other Obsidian Portal users, or keep your information private so only you can access it. 

## How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by using your username and password to log onto the website [http://www.obsidianportal.com](http://www.obsidianportal.com/) or by contacting us at [support@obsidianportal.com](mailto:support@obsidianportal.com) We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. 

You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error. 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

## Your Consent

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Obsidian Portal. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post a notice in our site announcements so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

## How To Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please email us at [support@obsidianportal.com](mailto:support@obsidianportal.com)
